berkeley.edu 2018-10-31

# Privacy Policy | University of California, Berkeley

The University of California, Berkeley is committed to protecting the privacy and accuracy of confidential information to the extent possible, subject to provisions of state and federal law. Other than as required by laws that guarantee public access to certain types of information, or in response to subpoenas or other legal instruments that authorize access, personal information is not actively shared. In particular, we do not re-distribute or sell personal information collected on our web servers.

The University of California, Berkeley is committed to protecting the privacy and accuracy of confidential information to the extent possible, subject to provisions of state and federal law. Other than as required by laws that guarantee public access to certain types of information, or in response to subpoenas or other legal instruments that authorize access, personal information is not actively shared. In particular, we do not re-distribute or sell personal information collected on our web servers.

## Information Collected

Our web servers log the following information:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address of computer being used
  * Web pages requested
  * Referring web page
  * Browser used
  * Date and time

This website does not associate this data with individual user identities. 

## Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

This website uses cookies for session maintenance: they allow us to see which pages a given user visited, but do not have any identifying information about the user. 

## Analytics partners

We partner with multiple third-party analytics providers to help us understand how visitors use our sites. We use this information to improve our content and your experience visiting our site. In order to generate this information, these analytics partners set their own cookies. We do not pass any personally identifying information about users to our partners. 

### Google Analytics

[How Google uses information from sites that use Google Analytics.](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) Google does not combine, match or cross-reference information from Google Analytics with any other user information.

### Siteimprove

[How Siteimprove uses information from sites that use Siteimprove Analytics](https://support.siteimprove.com/hc/en-gb/articles/115000070092-Analytics-Technical-Specifications) and [Siteimprove’s privacy policy.](https://siteimprove.com/en/privacy/privacy-policy/)

### Chartbeat

[How Chartbeat uses information from sites that use Chartbeat](https://chartbeat.com/gdpr/#how-chartbeat-products-use-data) and [Chartbeat’s Privacy Policy](https://chartbeat.com/privacy/).

## Opting out

You can configure your browser to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from websites you visit. Also, [Google offers a browser extension to opt out of Google Analytics.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

## Webforms

This website uses webforms. Contact information from these webforms is used only to send material relating to the purpose for which it was collected and will not be sold to another party. This website will only use personal information collected from this site for the purpose of communicating with individuals who contact us via the site.

## Logins

Where logins are used to allow submission or editing of content, information associating those submissions with that particular login is stored.

### CalNet

Where CalNet authentication is used for login, the website receives only your CalNet user id, which is mapped to a local account.

## Distribution of collected information:

This website will not disclose, without your consent, personal information collected about you, except for certain explicit circumstances in which disclosure is required by law. This website will not distribute or sell personal information to third-party organizations.

## Scope

This Privacy Statement does not apply to any other UC Berkeley web sites. You should review the privacy statement posted on other UC Berkeley websites when you visit them.

## Responsibility for External Sites

This website may contain links to other websites. Some of those websites may be operated by third parties. We provide the links for your convenience, but we do not review, control, or monitor the privacy practices of websites operated by others. We are not responsible for the performance of websites operated by third parties or for your business dealings with them. Therefore, whenever you leave this website we recommend that you review each website’s privacy practices and make your own conclusions regarding the adequacy of these practices. While using this website, you may encounter hypertext links to the web pages of other UC Berkeley websites or organizations not directly affiliated with UC Berkeley. All UC Berkeley websites must comply with the Privacy Statement for UC Berkeley Websites, but may have refined the standard campus privacy statement to include additional or stronger privacy provisions. UC Berkeley does not control the content or information practices of external organizations. We recommend you review the privacy statements of these organizations.

## Privacy Statement Revisions

We may change this Privacy Statement at any time and for any reason. We encourage you to review this Privacy Statement each time you visit the website. If we make a significant change to our Privacy Statement, we will post a notice on the homepage of our web site for a period of time after the change is made.

This Privacy Statement was last revised on July 5, 2018. 

## How to contact us:

Email: [webmaster@berkeley.edu](mailto:webmaster@berkeley.edu)
